Ankitha Sai Venkata

Seattle, WA ankithavenkata@gmail.com (425)-894-1046 LinkedIn Work Status: US Citizen Website

I am a Google Certified Cybersecurity Professional, ISC2 Certified in Cybersecurity (CC) and Valedictorian of the UW MSIS Class of 2023. I specialized in Security, Data Analytics and Business Intelligence and am currently looking for roles in Security Analytics and Compliance. My engineering background has laid for me a foundation in communication systems and network security while my 2+ years of work experience have allowed me to gain hands-on experience with log analysis, intrusion detection systems and other security tools. Working on two different continents has given me the unique ability to navigate ambiguity, lead teams with diverse opinions and strengthened my technical acumen and I now look forward to discussing how I can add value to your team.

EDUCATION

University of Washington - Michael G. Foster School of Business

Seattle, WA

Master of Science in Information Systems, GPA: 3.96/4.0 (Class Valedictorian)

June 2022 – June 2023

Relevant Coursework: Information Security, Security Policy and Governance, Cloud Computing

BITS Pilani University Hyderabad, India

B.Eng Electronics and Communication Engineering

Aug 2017 – Aug 2021

Relevant Coursework: Communication Networks, Cryptography, Information Theory and Coding

WORK HISTORY

Fortuna Identity
Data Analyst

Nashville, TN
July 2021 – Feb 2022

Cybersecurity startup specializing in Identity and Access Management for healthcare institutions

- Implemented data mining techniques in Python such as Frequent Pattern Growth Mining to improve the Intrusion Detection System (IDS) and reduced the number of false positives, saving 20 man hours per week
- Worked **cross-functionally** with the business team and engineering team to conduct **market research** and designed dashboards for 3 types of stakeholders to visualize performance metrics
- Simulated an ETL data pipeline using R Shiny and developed a GUI to display 10 proposed dashboard

Airmeet Bangalore, India

Business Analyst Intern

Jan 2021 – June 2021

- Handled all 40 clientele in the APAC and MEA regions, managing client relations and over \$350K of business
- Harnessed the use of **CRM software**, Tableau visualizations and Metabase queries to analyze company data and made **data-driven decisions** on customer expansion, lining up \$100K in the pipeline for the next quarter

Fortuna Identity Hyderabad, India

Data Analyst Intern

May 2020 – July 2020

- Conducted **log analysis** by utilizing ELK Stack and Wireshark to analyze tcpdump logs for trends amongst data packets that were raising false positive alerts
- Implemented a contextual signature database in Python for the IDS based on the metadata of safe packets
- Successfully filtered out false positive alerts bringing down the total alerts from 8.5 million to 50K per day

SKILLS

- Certifications: AWS Cloud Practitioner, ISC2 Certified in Cybersecurity (CC), Google Cybersecurity Certificate
- Programming Languages: SQL, Python (Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn), R (Dplyr, Ggplot2, Caret)
- Tools: Tableau, MS Excel, MS Access, Metabase, ELK Stack, RethinkDB, Wireshark, tcpdump, Suricata, LINUX
- Areas: Information Security, Security Analytics, Data Governance Risk and Compliance (GRC), Data Analytics, Machine Learning, Quantitative Methods, NIST, Intrusion Detection System (IDS), Log Analysis, SIEM
- Languages: English, Telugu, Hindi, French

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE & EXTRACURRICULARS

Girl Up Amara, Head of Publicity

Aug 2020 - Aug 2021

Led a team of 15 people in a United Nations initiative to raise awareness on issues through outreach campaigns

BITSMUN Hyderabad, Head of Professional Events

May 2019 – May 2020

Spearheaded a new initiative to organize a large-scale event for an audience of over 500 people